Kama Sutra: A Tale of Love is a drama, history,
romance film directed by Mira Nair.
Tara and Maya are inseparable, with the same tastes, habits, and hobbies.
Years later, the two have matured but have maintained their friendship.
Tara marries local prince Raj Singh, who succeeds the throne as the sole heir.
After the marriage, Raj seeks another female to satisfy his sexual desires, with his sights
settling on Maya, putting a perhaps unforgivable strain on a longtime friendship.
Maya, played by Indira Varma.
Tara, the Queen, played by Sarita Choudhury.
Jai Kumar, played by Ramon Tikaram.
Raj Singh, played by Naveen Andrews.
Rasa Devi, teacher of the Kama Sutra, played by Rekha.
Biki, played by Khalid Tyabji.
Kama Sutra: A Tale of Love is a 1996 historical erotic romance film
co-written, co-produced, and directed by Mira Nair.
The first portion of the film is based on "Utran" ("Hand Me Downs"), a
short story in Urdu by the Indian writer Wajida Tabassum.
The film takes its title from the ancient Hindu text, the Kama
Sutra but has no relationship with the text.
It stars Naveen Andrews, Sarita Choudhury, Ramon
Tikaram, Rekha and Indira Varma.
The English-language film was produced by Indian,
British, German and Japanese studios.
Declan Quinn won the 1998 Independent Spirit Award for Best
Cinematography for his work in the film.
Kama Sutra was nominated for the Golden Seashell award at the 1996 San Sebastián
International Film Festival and was screened at the Cannes Film Festival.
The film generated controversy at the time of its release and was
banned in India due to its erotic theme and sexual content.
The film explores themes of poetry, eroticism, seduction, india, woman director.
The tone is emotional.